# Do Lac Tuan

Date of birth Nov 13, 1996

**Gender** Male

**Phone** 0904835820

Email lactuannn@gmail.com

Address Hanoi, Vietnam

Website https://www.linkedin.com/in/do-lac-tuan-b75a2a167/

### **ABOUT ME**

I am one of the lucky ones who determined passion and career soon. I have started studying and programming from the early years of high school and improve it until now.

Up to now, I've had more 4 years of experience in developing iOS apps.

My goal is to build awesome mobile apps so that when people mention something, my app will be a good choice for them.

### **EDUCATION**

2016 - 2016	TechMaster iOS Application Developer
	<ul> <li>- During the time I studied here, I learned:</li> <li>+ Knowledge in OOP</li> <li>+ Understanding of iOS SDK</li> <li>+ Good in Swift</li> </ul>
	<ul> <li>Experienced in working with :</li> <li>+ Network request and RESTful APIs</li> <li>+ Interface builder and Auto layout</li> <li>+ Custom UI, Animatons</li> <li>+ 3rd libraries as Alamfire, SwiftyJSON, Firebase, FacebookSDK,etc</li> </ul>

### **SKILLS**

Programming Languages	Swift: Good
Framework	UIKit: Good     SwiftUI: Basic
Tools	Familiar with XCode
Languages	<ul><li> Vietnamese: Native language</li><li> English: Good at reading and listening</li></ul>
Architecture Pattern	• MVC, MVP, MVVM.

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

June 2020 - Sep 2022

ITSol

iOS Developer

I work as iOS developer onsite in Viettel Business Solutions. I joined some products like ePass ETC, Sổ sức khoẻ điện tử. During my time here I have accumulated a lot of knowledge about mobile applications especially iOS, architectures like MVVM and RxSwift.

Oct 2019 - June 2020

**Minh Phuc Software** 

iOS Developer

I work as iOS developer. I joined some products include maintaining, developing. During my time here I have accumulated a lot of knowledge about submiting app to appstore, enroll to Apple Developer Enterprise Program.

Sep 2018 - July 2019

**NTQ-Solution** 

iOS Developer

I work in a team of 8 members and including 2 iOS engineers. I joined some products include maintaining, developing. During my time here I have accumulated a lot of knowledge about mobile applications especially iOS, architectures like MVP. I learned here the professional working processes in developing outsourcing projects.

Nov 2017 - Sep 2018

**Smart Media** 

iOS Developer

I work in a mobile team of 5 members and including 2 iOS engineers. My team has created some high-quality products like: Buum, VNGate. During my time here I have accumulated a lot of UI/UX knowledge about mobile applications especially iOS.

#### **PROJECTS**

#### ePassDashboard iPad

(Dec 2020 - Now)

Customer	Viettel Business Solutions
Description	- An in-house application display all of ePass's data for iPad
Team size	
My position	iOS Programmer
My responsibilities	- Develop: All screens - Optimize code - Fix bugs
Technologies used	- Swift 5 - Moya, SwiftUI, Charts,

#### **ePassDashboard**

(Dec 2020 - Now)

Customer	Viettel Business Solutions
Description	- An in-house application display all of ePass's data
Team size	
My position	iOS Programmer

My responsibilities	- Develop: All screens - Optimize code - Fix bugs
Technologies used	- Swift 5 - Moya, Charts,

### **ePass**

(June 2020 - Oct 2020)

Customer	Viettel Business Solutions
Description	- An application for electronic toll collection ( ETC ) - Appstore link: https://apps.apple.com/us/app/epass/id1535426844
Team size	
My position	iOS Programmer
My responsibilities	- Develop: UI Develop buy ticket Develop histories, Optimize code - Submit to appstore - Fix bugs
Technologies used	- Swift 4 - Alamofire,VTPay,

## Sổ sức khoẻ điện tử

(Oct 2020 - Nov 2020)

Customer	Viettel Business Solutions
Description	- An application of Ministry of Health (VietNam) - Appstore link: https://apps.apple.com/vn/app/s%E1%BB%95-s%E1%BB%A9c-kh%E1%BB%8Fe-%C4%91i%E1%BB%87n-t%E1%BB%AD/id1555911794?I=vi
Team size	
My position	iOS Programmer
My responsibilities	- Develop account setting - Develop medical records - Fix bugs
Technologies used	- Swift 5 - Alamofire - RxSwift

### **MPCC**

(Oct 2019 - Feb 2020)

Customer	Minh Phuc Telecom
Description	<ul> <li>- A contact center application for enterprise.</li> <li>- Make and receive calls from app.</li> <li>- Record calls and save customer's information.</li> <li>- History call, etc</li> <li>- Appstore link: https://apps.apple.com/us/app/mpcc/id1490242445</li> </ul>
Team size	
My position	iOS Programmer
My responsibilities	- Develop: some screens Maintaince Optimize code - Fix bugs - Submit to appstore
Technologies used	- Swift 4 - Alamofire, ObjectMapper, Fabric, Crashlytics, Kingfisher, Abto phone, RabbitMQ, Firebase,

## MP Quan ly tai san

## (Dec 2019 - Dec 2019)

Customer	Minh Phuc Software
Description	- A in-house application for employee to manage assets of company - Appstore link : https://apps.apple.com/us/app/mp-quảnlý-tài-sản/id1449438785? I=vi&ls=1
Team size	
My position	iOS Programmer
My responsibilities	- Maintaince Optimize code - Fix bugs - Submit to appstore
Technologies used	- Swift 4 - Alamofire, ObjectMapper

## **VNGate**

(April 2018 - May 2018)

Customer	Smart Media
Description	- An application for Korean in Vietnam reading newspapers and asking with live chat Appstore link: https://itunes.apple.com/kr/app/appname/id1313690742
Team size	4
My position	iOS Programmer
My responsibilities	- Develop UI: All screens - Design and develop user's features - Search posts Invite other users - Like, dislike, comment, share post Chat for users with admin Optimize code - Fix bugs - Build testing versions to TestFlight
Technologies used	- Swift 4 - Alamofire, ObjectMapper, Kingfisher, Onesignal, SnapKit,FacebookSDK, Fabric, Crashlytics etc

### Buum

(Nov 2017 - April 2018)

Customer	Smart Media
Description	- A Karaoke app - Add polish to user's vocals with studio effects - Appstore link: https://itunes.apple.com/vn/app/buummusic-studio/id1246645850
Team size	4
My position	iOS Programmer
My responsibilities	- Add more required futures - Develop UI: Some screens - Develop user's features - Fix bugs - Optimize code
Technologies used	- Swift 4 - Alamofire, Kingfisher, ObjectMapper, Realm, etc